<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science Portfolio on Andrew Bruneel</title>
    <link>https://ABruneel04.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science Portfolio on Andrew Bruneel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ABruneel04.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Sale Price prediction using Linear Regression</title>
      <link>https://ABruneel04.github.io/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ABruneel04.github.io/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Using Machine Learning, I explored the significance of a multitude of features in predicting the sale price of a given house. By the end of my work I was able to complete a Linear Regression model that performed as well as other top LR models (based on MSE).
Worked with over 70 features, trimming down the amount of predictors with feature engineering and eventually using numerical values for correlation to evaluate features that would be used Took the list of correlated features and developed Linear Regression models to fit against the training data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Quarterback Data Analysis</title>
      <link>https://ABruneel04.github.io/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ABruneel04.github.io/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>This project was a chance to work on web scraping and extracting meaning from data. I collected 5 seasons of fantasy football quarterback statistics from 2016-2020 and used visualizations to understand how different statistics interact with each other in ways that may not be obvious.
Assembled 7,200 data points of fantasy football quarterback statistics from an online database with BeautifulSoup and cleaned data to later be visualized Engineered features inside of a pandas DataFrame, and used statistics to determine the highest scoring players over a five year period in both total points and points per game Working to implement machine learning to predict a player&amp;rsquo;s rank in future seasons Link to my GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 3: Numerical Dynamo Modeling (Senior Thesis)</title>
      <link>https://ABruneel04.github.io/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ABruneel04.github.io/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>This was my first chance to implement Data Science principles into my work. I used Python to visualize parameters involved in dynamo generation for celestial bodies throughout our solar system. Using these visualizations, I was able to predict a given bodies&amp;rsquo; potential for sustaining life.
Used MagIC (an open-source code) to simulate the fluid physics occurring within planetary dynamos Compared the physics against benchmark cases that have been previously verified Varied the magnetic Prandtl parameter and determined if a dynamo could be sustained (and thus life) under those conditions Transferred data to python and created plots for each tested case Attached the thesis write-up explaining the physics and conclusions as well as the graphs in the GitHub repository linked here:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://ABruneel04.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ABruneel04.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Looking for internship opportunities in the field of Data Science. I have a strong quantitative background established from my time as an undergraduate Physics major/Computer Science minor, and I am now pursuing a Master&amp;rsquo;s of Science in Applied Data Science at the University of Southern California. I have experience with several programming languages, namely Python, along with SQL, Java, and C++. My recent work has involved data collection, data visualization, feature engineering, and machine learning through personal projects and certifications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://ABruneel04.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ABruneel04.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Here are some ways to get into contact with me:
Platform URL E-mail: abruneel04@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrew-bruneel/ GitHub: https://github.com/ABruneel04 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
